Atlanta, USA

Professional Profile

Full-stack Software Engineer with more than 10 years of experience building API/Client-first services development.

In-depth experience in multiple domains, including music/audio broadcast, low-latency (high-throughput) distributed systems and caches, real-time ad-delivery services, and location-based and data-mobilization software solutions.

EXPERIENCE

• Amazon.com, Inc.

Jan 2020 - Present

Software Development Engineer II

- Ads Filtering & Eligibility Services: Designed a globally-accessible Ad Eligibility API handling hundreds of transactions per second using API Gateway, Lambda, and **DynamoDB GlobalTables**, delivering cross-regional distributed solution.
 - Developing next generation Ads Filtering service using various technologies such as AWS ECS and SQS.
- Amp: Amazon Music's Amp in an infinite-dial digital radio broadcast mobile application. Amp allows users to create a show, go live, play music, and take in call-in guests all with simple flow and within minutes.
 - Lead engineer developing Amp Android app and migrating Amp iOS app to hybrid **ReactNative**-based architecture with native core components in both **iOS Swift** and **Android Kotlin**.
 - Team leader of Creator Studio & Call-in experience full-stack development maintaining iOS/Swift client and backend system using AWS Lambda, Chime APIs, **Elastic-Containers on Fargate** microservices, and AWS AppSync **GraphQL**.
 - Led group of engineers to develop iOS Bluetooth/audio solution which was filed as Patent P78152 SWITCHING WIRELESS PROFILES IN RESPONSE TO TRIGGER EVENTS.
- FenixSPService: Core orchestration engine that serves Sponsored-Products Ads on Amazon.com retail website and mobile app worldwide. Fenix is a high-throughput low-latency real-time distributed service that delivers curated ads per user on Amazon.com pages and apps. Utilizing Java and Spring MVC.
- FenixSPService on Native AWS (NAWS): Delivered the first proof-of-concept demonstrating the ability to boot up FenixSPService on the public/native offering of AWS ecosystem.
 - Identified +20 technical blockers, led team of engineers to develop simple workaround solutions, and eventually provided a risk-mitigation path for the actual migration and deployment of the service.
 - Launching FenixSPService on Native AWS was later featured in AWS re:Invent 2021 Under the hood at Amazon Ads.
- **DevOps and OnCall**: Participate in on-call and deployment shepherd rotations. Improve pipelines and monitoring to implement best practices of CI/CD.

• Webalo, Inc. Jul 2016 - Dec 2019

Software Engineer

- HTML Toolkit: Designed the architecture for a new HTML-based platform-agnostic UI widget rendering toolkit.

 Led a team of engineers to develop and migrate Webalo's User Agent applications to the new toolkit and retire the Java Canvas-based toolkit. Utilizing TypeScript and Web Components in Angular 7, Bootstrap, and JavaScript/CSS.
- CI/CD: Automated system build, execution of integration and end-to-end tests, and binaries distribution through using Git Hooks, Jenkins, and Shell scripting.
- Unit & Integration testing: Spearheaded the effort to set up and design system testing framework for developing integration tests.
 - Utilizing **TestNG** and **Mockito** for module testing and **Selenium** for end-to-end testing.
- Google, Inc.

Aug 2015 - Nov 2015

Software Engineering Intern

• Sandlot: As part of the G-Tech team, integrated sentiment prediction into Google's partners management tool. Responsible for the design and implementation of the new feature using Python and AngularJS.

• Wireless Stars, LLC

Software Engineer

• ARTS: System for road traffic estimation based on user cell-phone data analytics. Building Android SDK for location and sensor data collection.

Collaborating with research team on developing production ready algorithms and modules for data processing back-end system using **Spring Boot** and data pipeline through Apache Camel.

Responsible for implementation and testing of Kalman-filter user speed estimator.

Utilized PostGIS to implement spatial queries consumed by various modules of the system.

Implemented **Android** app that uses traffic SDK to push data to the back-end and query the system for estimated traffic state. The application was used by business team for demo/presentation and by the research team for system evaluation.

• EYE360: Augmented reality application providing bi-directional user interaction built using Unity3D and Qualcomm Vuforia SDK

• B-Yond

Consultant Engineer

• National ID Segmentation: Designed and implemented customer license management in Python using JWT, obfuscation, and elliptic curve cryptography.

Designed run-time transaction management using symmetric key cryptography.

Advised ML and junior engineers on deployment strategies and post deployment monitoring, support, and CI/CD.

• Coptic Academy, NGO

Part-time Back-end Engineer

- R&D: Evaluated the use of technologies like HashiCorp and JWT for implementing client/service secured communications.
- **CPlanner**: Maintained RESTful data-serving back-end for Coptic Planner mobile app. Responsibilities include REST API extension using **Spring Boot** and Hibernate, deployment to production server and bug troubleshooting/fixing. Optimization of back-end operations and SQL queries.
- **CMentor**: Set up, designed, and implemented RESTful back-end for Coptic Mentor mobile app using Spring Boot and **Hibernate**.
- Batch-processor: Designed and implemented data batch-processor driven by cron jobs for consuming system data, via optimized SQL queries, and delivering custom notification in Java and shell scripts.

• Alexandria University

Sep 2012 - Jan 2013

Oct 2013 - May 2015

 $Teaching\ Assistant$

o In Special Scientific Program (SSP): Teaching Introduction to Databases and Numerical Analysis courses.

• Innuva, IT Jul 2011 - Oct 2011

Game Developer Trainee

• **3D** shooting game: Game design and implementation using **Unity3D** game engine. The game logic is being implemented using JavaScript for Unity3D.

Tools & Frameworks ¹

- Languages: Java Swift Python TypeScript HTML/JavaScript/CSS SQL
- Frameworks: iOS ReactNative Spring MVC/Boot Bootstrap Angular 7 Unity3D Android
- CI/CD: CDK- Jenkins TestNG Selenium Mockito/PowerMock Jasmine/Karma

EDUCATION

• Alexandria University, Faculty of Engineering

Sep 2007 – Jul 2012

B.Sc. Computer and Systems Engineering

CONTINUOUS EDUCATION ²

- Architecture and Developing on AWS: AWS Hands-on Training
- DevOps on AWS: AWS Hands-on Training
- Security Engineering on AWS: AWS Hands-on Training
- Programming Languages: Coursera Washington Uni
- Introduction to Functional Programming in Scala: Coursera
- Applied Cryptography: Udacity
- Introduction to Cryptography: Coursera Stanford
- Introduction to Recommender Systems: Coursera Uni of Minnesota
- Algorithms Design and Analysis: Coursera Stanford
- CSMM.102x Machine Learning: Edx ColumbiaX
- CSMM.101x Artificial Intelligence: Edx ColumbiaX
- Introduction to AI for Robotics: Udacity
- Machine Learning: Coursera
- Coding the Matrix: Coursera
- Scalable Machine Learning: Edx

¹Technologies are listed in decreasing order of experience.

²Certificates are available upon request.